Politics would never be the same.
Game Change is a tv movie, drama, comedy film directed by Jay Roach.
During the Republican run of the 2008 Presidential election, candidate John McCain picks a
relative unknown, Alaskan governor Sarah Palin, to be his running mate.
As the campaign kicks into high gear, her lack of experience, in both political
and media savvy, becomes a drain upon McCain and his strategists.
Sarah Palin, played by Julianne Moore.
Steve Schmidt, played by Woody Harrelson.
John McCain, played by Ed Harris.
Rick Davis, played by Peter MacNicol.
Mark Salter, played by Jamey Sheridan.
Nicolle Wallace, played by Sarah Paulson.
Game Change is a 2012 American political drama television film based on events of the 2008 United States presidential election campaign of John McCain, directed by Jay
Roach and written by Danny Strong, based on the 2010 book of the same title documenting the campaign by political journalists Mark Halperin and John Heilemann.
The film stars Julianne Moore, Woody Harrelson, and Ed Harris, and focuses on the chapters about the selection and performance of
Governor of Alaska Sarah Palin (Moore) as running mate to Senator John McCain (Harris) in the presidential campaign.
The plot features a 2010 interview of the campaign's senior strategist Steve Schmidt (Harrelson), using
flashbacks to portray McCain and Palin during their ultimately unsuccessful campaign.
The film aired on HBO on March 10, 2012.
It was well received by critics, with Moore's
portrayal of Palin garnering praise.
Schmidt praised the film, while Palin and McCain both
stated they had no intention of seeing it.
Alessandra Stanley of The New York Times described Moore's depiction of Palin as "a sharp-edged but not unsympathetic portrait of a flawed heroine, colored more in pity than in admiration."
Game Change has earned many awards, including a
Critics' Choice Television Award, a Directors Guild of America Award, a Golden Nymph Award, three Golden Globe Awards, a Producers Guild of America Award, five Primetime Emmy Awards, and a Writers Guild of America Award.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.